<tool id="DatUtil">
	<img src="CMProRC.png" width="233" height="142"/>
	<img src="DatUtil.png" width="81" height="40"/>

	<name>DatUtil</name>
	<version>v2.31</version>
	<status>Updated</status>
	<date>01/01/2007</date>

	<description>Data file creation/conversion tool</description>

	<comment>
		<p>
			DatUtil was created to aid in the creation of dat files for Rom Managers such as ClrMamePro and RomCenter (Roman Scherzer / Eric Bole-Feysot). It can convert between formats, extract individual games (and optionally their clones) and cleanse dats. It supports a variety of formats...<br />
			<br />
			<b>Load and Save:</b><br />
			<br />
			- MAME ListInfo (ClrMamePro, MAME, MESS, RAINE, Shark)<br />
			- RomCenter 2.50<br />
			- MAME ListXML (MAME and MESS)<br />
			- Tab Delimited<br />
			<br />
			<b>Load only:</b><br />
			<br />
			- RomCenter 1.90<br />
			- RomCenter 2.00<br />
			- Nebula Drivers<br />
			- Calice Drivers<br />
			- Zinc --list-sets<br />
			- GNGEO romrc<br />
			- ClrMame Log<br />
			- Folder Scan (subdirectories and zips)<br />
			<br />
			<b>Save only:</b><br />
			<br />
			- MAME GameList<br />
			- Title List (for listing game titles - used by CPS-2 readme and RAINE docs)<br />
			- RomCenter Sublist
		</p>
	</comment>

	<downloads>
		<download>
			<file name="dutil231.zip" size="179"/>
		</download>
	</downloads>

	<revisions>
		<revision>
			<date>1 January 2007</date>
			<version>v2.31</version>
			<comment>
				- Uses DatLib v2.20.<br/>
				- Added 'prune' option (-p) for removing roms, disk and/or samples<br/>
            			- Added 'incorporate' option (-I) to assist in combining datafiles
			</comment>
		</revision>

		<revision>
			<date>17 October 2006</date>
			<version>v2.30</version>
			<comment>
				- Uses DatLib v2.18.<br/>
				- More intelligent DTD creation when saving in ListXML format<br/>
				- Added support for game/display (MAME v0.107)<br/>
				- Added support for game/input/control (MAME v0.107)<br/>
				- Added support for emulator/build (MAME+MESS v0.101u4 upwards)<br/>
				- Added support for driver/savestate (MAME v0.101u1 upwards)<br/>
            			- Note: The above changes affect the tab delimited format!
            			- Added 'delimited.sql' as an example of loading dats into MySQL
    			</comment>
		</revision>

		<revision>
			<date>16 July 2006</date>
			<version>v2.29</version>
			<comment>
				- Uses DatLib v2.17.<br/>
				- Fixed bug that caused the DatUtil -g and -r options to crash
    			</comment>
		</revision>

		<revision>
			<date>11 July 2006</date>
			<version>v2.28</version>
			<comment>
				- Uses DatLib v2.16.<br/>
				- Fixed bug that messed up internal indices (affected crc matching)<br/>
				- More intelligent directory scanner (regarding samples and CHDs)<br/>
				- Removed 64MB file limit from directory scanner (reads 1MB blocks)
    			</comment>
		</revision>

		<revision>
			<date>13 January 2006</date>
			<version>v2.27</version>
			<comment>
				- Uses DatLib v2.15.<br />
            			- Last release would not load data files less than 4KB in size!
    			</comment>
		</revision>

		<revision>
			<date>12 January 2006</date>
			<version>v2.26</version>
			<comment>
				- Uses DatLib v2.14.<br />
				- Added a save-only format to imitate MAME's gamelist.txt file.<br />
				- File identification is now done by loading just the first 4KB.<br />
				- Added a list of supported save-formats to the command line help.
    			</comment>
		</revision>

		<revision>
			<date>6 December 2005</date>
			<version>v2.25</version>
			<comment>
				- Uses DatLib v2.13.<br />
				- DatLib v2.12 broke the RomCenter drivers (now fixed).
    			</comment>
		</revision>

		<revision>
			<date>5 December 2005</date>
			<version>v2.24</version>
			<comment>
				- Uses DatLib v2.12.<br />
				- Fixed a rare crash (if the longest line in the dat was the last).<br />
				- Fixed a problem loading RomCenter data files containing [].
    			</comment>
		</revision>

		<revision>
			<date>13 November 2005</date>
			<version>v2.23</version>
			<comment>
				- Uses DatLib v2.11.<br />
				- Added support for 'board', 'colordeep', 'credits' and 'archive'<br />
				(fully supported by ListInfo, ListXML and Delimited formats).<br />
				- M1 XML loader now retains the 'board' information (see above).<br />
				- M1 XML will not use hex for ROM sizes after all... changed back!<br />
				- Improved the way that the Nebula driver handles Neo-Geo ROMs.<br />
				- Fixed Nebula Jukebox driver for Neo-Geo ROMs (broken in v2.7).
    			</comment>
		</revision>

		<revision>
			<date>31 October 2005</date>
			<version>v2.22</version>
			<comment>
				- Uses DatLib v2.10.<br />
				- Fixed identification of ListXML for MAME+MESS v0.101u4 onwards.<br />
				- Added the '-q' option (to save Listinfo with quotes throughout).
    			</comment>
		</revision>

		<revision>
			<date>28 October 2005</date>
			<version>v2.21</version>
			<comment>
				- Uses DatLib v2.9.<br />
				- M1 XML will use hex for ROM sizes. Changed driver accordingly.<br />
				- Now reports duplicate game descriptions and CRCs (i.e. ROMs).
			</comment>
		</revision>

		<revision>
			<date>5 October 2005</date>
			<version>v2.20</version>
			<comment>
				- Uses DatLib v2.8.<br />
				- Improved the logerror() function (used for reporting ZIP errors).<br />
				- Added support for M1's XML format (when it becomes available).
			</comment>
		</revision>

		<revision>
			<date>17 September 2005</date>
			<version>v2.19</version>
			<comment>
				- Uses DatLib v2.7.<br />
				- Compiled with zlib 1.3.<br />
				- Improved Neo-Geo handling for the Nebula driver.<br />
				- Improved 'romof' handling for RomCenter 2 driver (during loading).
			</comment>
		</revision>

		<revision>
			<date>31 August 2005</date>
			<version>v2.18</version>
			<comment>
				- Uses DatLib v2.6. <br />
				- Fixed a 'hang' that occurred with circular cloneof relationships.<br />
			</comment>
		</revision>

		<revision>
			<date>10 April 2005</date>
			<version>v2.17</version>
			<comment>
				- Uses DatLib v2.5. <br />
				- Excludes disks from RomCenter data files (-k will include them).<br />
			</comment>
		</revision>

		<revision>
			<date>25 March 2005</date>
			<version>v2.16</version>
			<comment>
				- Uses DatLib v2.4. <br />
				- Fixed another crash with datutil -X and 'forcemerging full'. <br />
				- Changed the delimited format to use \N for NULLs. <br />
				- Changed the delimited format so that all types are 'game_*'. <br />
				- Changed the delimited format so that games include 'runnable'. <br />
				- Added save support for a DISK section in the RomCenter format. <br />
				- Added several aliases for the output formats (see notes above).<br />
			</comment>
		</revision>

		<revision>
			<date>7 March 2005</date>
			<version>v2.15</version>
			<comment>
				- Uses DatLib v2.3. <br />
				- Fixed a problem with counting parents (happened with DatUtil -X). <br />
				- This also avoids a crash with datutil -X and 'forcemerging full'. <br />
			</comment>
		</revision>

		<revision>
			<date>28 February 2005</date>
			<version>v2.14</version>
			<comment>
				- Uses DatLib v2.2. <br />
				- Added support for tab delimited files ('-f delimited'). <br />
				- Added save-support for RomCenter sublists ('-f sublist'). <br />
				- Added \t support to the listinfo driver (and tab delimited). <br />
				- Fixed problem of unrecognised escape sequences looping forever! <br />
			</comment>
		</revision>

		<revision>
			<date>22 February 2005</date>
			<version>v2.13</version>
			<comment>
				- Uses DatLib v2.1. <br />
				- Added a test option (-t) where nothing is actually saved. <br />
				- Log file is now automatically deleted if it is empty. <br />
				- Made selections more flexible (can now use commas as a delimiter). <br />
				- Added warnings for invalid game/sourcefile selections (-g and -G). <br />
				- Added warning messages for duplicated games (i.e. same game name). <br />
				- Can identify listinfo files even if they only contain resources. <br />
				- The 'remove clones' option will retain the original dat format. <br />
				- Fixed a crash caused by empty selection files (the '@' syntax). <br />
				- Saving a RomCenter datafile will now report an error if the '&not;' <br />
				symbol is used in the game or ROM details (i.e. the dat is bad). <br />
				- Changed the error messages that are given when files are missing. <br />
				- Changed the command line help a little bit (explanation of -!). <br />
			</comment>
		</revision>

		<revision>
			<date>15 February 2005</date>
			<version>v2.12</version>
			<comment>
				- Uses DatLib v2.0. <br />
				- Compiled with GCC 3.4.2 (previously used GCC 3.2.3). <br />
				- Rewrote the manual, please read it from start to end. ;) <br />
				- Changed the summary of switches produced by DatUtil -?. <br />
				- Added the -k option to keep all details (chips, dips, etc). <br />
				- Added the -G option to select games from a specified sourcefile. <br />
				- Added the -! option so that -g and -G can be used as exclusions. <br />
				- Added the -X option to switch off 'fix merging' (use with -g). <br />
				- Added the -D option to switch off 'remove duplicates' (as above). <br />
				- Removed the -z and -y options as they are redundant now. <br />
				<br />
				- DatLib v2.0 (enhancements relating to DatUtil): <br />
				- Added 'sourcefile' support to the listinfo and listxml drivers. <br />
				- Supports all known details in listinfo and listxml (-k option). <br />
				- N.b. ROM region is not loaded unless using the datutil -k option. <br />
				- Supports 'history' entries (when using the -k option). <br />
				- Added support for \\, \n, \xXX and \" in ListInfo (e.g. history). <br />
				- Improved entity handling (e.g. &amp;amp; &amp;#X;) in the ListXML parser. <br />
				- Supports 2 additional MESS objects (devices and extensions). <br />
				- DatLib can now save data in listxml format (MAME and MESS). <br />
				- Complemented CRCs are reported (should use flags nodump instead). <br />
				- Added checks for MD5 and SHA1 conflicts (CRCs already checked). <br />
				- Added support for external selection files with the @ symbol. <br />
				- Removed the hack made in DatLib v1.13 for Calice drivers. <br />
				- Removed funny size and missing year checks (pretty useless now).<br />
			</comment>
		</revision>

		<revision>
			<date>16 January 2005</date>
			<version>v2.11</version>
			<comment>
				- Uses DatLib v1.14. <br />
				- Added support for the GNGEO romrc file. <br />
				- Increased maximum ROM size to 64MB (used when scanning folders).<br />
			</comment>
		</revision>

		<revision>
			<date>4 January 2005</date>
			<version>v2.10</version>
			<comment>
				- Uses DatLib v1.13. <br />
				- Added support for Calice drivers. <br />
			</comment>
		</revision>

		<revision>
			<date>25 November 2004</date>
			<version>v2.9</version>
			<comment>
				- Uses DatLib v1.12. <br />
				- Improved the handling of CRC conflicts within the 'fix merging'. <br />
			</comment>
		</revision>

		<revision>
			<date>26 October 2004</date>
			<version>v2.8</version>
			<comment>
				- Uses DatLib v1.11. <br />
				- Added a parser for the ZiNc --list-sets. <br />
			</comment>
		</revision>

		<revision>
			<date>18 August 2004</date>
			<version>v2.7</version>
			<comment>
				- Uses DatLib v1.10. <br />
				- Better handling of 'clones of clones' when loading data files. <br />
			</comment>
		</revision>

		<revision>
			<date>30 July 2004</date>
			<version>v2.6</version>
			<comment>
				- Uses DatLib v1.9. <br />
				- Added full support for disk 'merge' and 'flags' information. <br />
			</comment>
		</revision>

		<revision>
			<date>22 July 2004</date>
			<version>v2.5</version>
			<comment>
				- Uses DatLib v1.8. <br />
				- Removed the need for xml2info by adding my own MAME XML parser. <br />
				- A nice side effect is that names like "Alien<sup>3</sup>: The Gun" work now! <br />
			</comment>
		</revision>

		<revision>
			<date>21 July 2004</date>
			<version>v2.4</version>
			<comment>
				- Uses DatLib v1.7 <br />
				- Added support for MESS XML. <br />
				- Directory scanner now supports CHDs (when in a game directory). <br />
				- Improved 'fix merging' (where clone ROMs are not in the parent). <br />
				- Enhanced 'fix merging' to work for disks (SHA1/MD5 are copied). <br />
				- Added check for SHA1/MD5 conflicts of disks across clones. <br />
			</comment>
		</revision>

		<revision>
			<date>17 July 2004</date>
			<version>v2.3</version>
			<comment>
				- Uses DatLib v1.5 <br />
				- Added the -j option for Nebula Jukebox (Z80 and Samples only). <br />
			</comment>
		</revision>

		<revision>
			<date>11 July 2004</date>
			<version>v2.2</version>
			<comment>
				- Uses DatLib v1.4: <br />
				- Added support for comments between games in CMPro data files. <br />
				- Added an option to ignore missing year information (-y). <br />
				- Added an option to select MD5 usage rather than SHA1 (-m). <br />
				Note that '-m' was previously used for the 'fix merging' option! <br />
				- Added an option to include missing info from another dat (-i). <br />
				Games: cloneof, romof, sampleof (good after using the -g option). <br />
				ROMs: size, crc, md5, sha1, flags (good for adding SHA1, etc). <br />
			</comment>
		</revision>

		<revision>
			<date>4 July 2004</date>
			<version>v2.1</version>
			<comment>
				- Added a message to say that the -m option is not required now. <br />
				- Uses DatLib v1.1: <br />
				- ClrMamePro/RomCenter header is now ignored when using OPTION_GAME. <br />
				- Removed a warning when you try using 'datutil -g &lt;resource> -c'. <br />
				- Added debug information to identify spurious warnings like above. <br />
				- Added the -x option to calculate SHA1/MD5 when scanning ZIPs. <br />
				- n.b. SHA1/MD5 used to be calculated by default in DatUtil v2.0. <br />
			</comment>
		</revision>

		<revision>
			<date>2 July 2004</date>
			<version>v2.0</version>
			<comment>
				Wow, I never thought I'd get around to this rewrite but here it is! <br />
				<br />
				Uses DatLib - The new library for handling dats of many formats <br />
				<br />
				- A generic dat structure with various loading and cleansing routines. <br />
				<br />
				- Far better memory handling. No longer uses huge blocks of fixed size memory. <br />
				<br />
				Info: DatUtil used to allocate almost 45MB for a dat when it was loaded. <br />
				This was without MD5/SHA1 support and for a limited number of games! <br />
				DatLib now allocates only what it really requires (which is usually <br />
				about twice the size of the dat file). <br />
				<br />
				- Multi-phase processing (pre-parse, parse, cleanse, save): <br />
				<br />
				- Pre-parser translates dat into an intermediate dat format. <br />
				- Parser interprets the intermediate format to populate the dat structure. <br />
				- Cleanser does things like 'lowercase', 'remove dups', 'fix merging', etc. <br />
				- Saving outputs the cleansed dat structure in the required output format. <br />
				<br />
				Note: The main difference is the addition of the pre-parser (which removes <br />
				common operations from the different dat parsers) and the separation <br />
				of the cleansing operations from the loader (they used to be embedded <br />
				in the various parsers, particularly painful for RomCenter format!). <br />
				<br />
				- No limit on the number of games, ROMs, disks, samples etc. <br />
				<br />
				- No limit on the length of file names, game titles, manufacturer names etc. <br />
				<br />
				- Improved size and CRC handling (now numeric, not text based). <br />
				<br />
				- Supports 'rebuildto' information for games. <br />
				<br />
				- Supports alternative checksums (MD5 and SHA1). <br />
				N.B. The directory scanner also generates MD5 and SHA1 checksums for files. <br />
				<br />
				- Supports 'region' information of ROMs. <br />
				<br />
				- Improved driver system for developers adding new dat formats. <br />
				<br />
				- Fully supports the latest RomCenter dat format (2.50). <br />
				<br />
				- Improved RomCenter parser is not case sensitive like the old one was. <br />
				<br />
				- All cleansing features can now be used with all supported formats. <br />
				<br />
				- Improved 'fix merging'. Now operates across clones, not just parent/clone. <br />
				Also fixes bad parent references and prevents clones of clones. <br />
				The feature is run by default when a data file is loaded into memory. <br />
				A summary of fixes is shown in datutil.log, use -v option for full details. <br />
				<br />
				- Duplicate ROMs are now removed when the data file is loaded into memory. <br />
				<br />
				- Added debugging information (to help me track down problems). <br />
				<br />
				- Removed alternate ROM support. It was only used by Shark and made data file <br />
				comparisons unnecessarily complicated! <br />
				<br />
				- Removed code that fixed the bad parent 'pc' in MESS dats (the default <br />
				'fix merging' code does the same job now but without being hard coded). <br />
				<br />
				- ClrMamePro log parser now supports disk images and alternative checksums. <br />
				<br />
				- Nebula parser is now much better. With the default 'fix merging' behaviour, <br />
				the data file that is generated should be almost usable now! <br />
				<br />
				- Improved baddump and nodump handling. <br />
				Also supports the syntax of MAME v0.68 (where the word 'flags' was missing). <br />
				<br />
				- Improved logging. Added a verbose (-v) option for even more detail! <br />
				<br />
				- You are given a warning if you try to convert a RomCenter data file where <br />
				the plugin is not 'arcade.dll'. It is likely that such a conversion will <br />
				not work correctly in ClrMamePro. <br />
				<br />
				- The -g and -c options can now be used on resources. You can therefore <br />
				extract games for neogeo, zn1, etc. (e.g. 'datutil -g cpzn1 -c mame.dat'). <br />
				<br />
				- Removed the dat comparison facility. Use MAMEDiff instead! <br />
				<br />
				- Added load support for MAME ListXML format (uses the xml2info tool). <br />
				<br />
				- Added a warning summary to datutil.log. <br />
				Warnings are for missing details, funny ROM sizes and CRC conflicts. <br />
				For full details of the warnings, use the DatUtil -v (verbose) option. <br />
				<br />
				- Added details of all information that is lost when saving in a different <br />
				format (e.g. Years and Manufacturers are lost when using RomCenter format). <br />
				<br />
				Unsupported formats - Not included in the rewrite as they are of little use! <br />
				<br />
				Load and Save: <br />
				<br />
				- Calice DRV (drivers) <br />
				<br />
				Load only: <br />
				<br />
				- Callus gamelist <br />
				- CPSE data (drivers) <br />
				- Mimic HWC (drivers) <br />
				- System16 GCS (drivers) <br />
				- Sparcade RAT (drivers) <br />
				- Retrocade Romlist <br />
				- JAS romlist <br />
				- JFF text <br />
			</comment>
		</revision>

		<revision>
			<date>26 February 2004</date>
			<version>v1.32</version>
			<comment>
				- Finally added disk support for MAME! <br />
			</comment>
		</revision>

		<revision>
			<date>31 January 2004</date>
			<version>v1.31</version>
			<comment>
				- When saving data files in listinfo format, 'crc 00000000' is now <br />
				written out as 'flags nodump'. <br />
			</comment>
		</revision>

		<revision>
			<date>24 January 2004</date>
			<version>v1.30</version>
			<comment>
				- Increased the maximum number of games from 5000 to 6000. <br />
				- Removed support for the old RomCenter 1 format... <br />
				The old format is inadequate for modern day MAME releases. <br />
				- Removed knowledge of the MAME resource names. RomCenter 2 data <br />
				files must therefore have a [RESOURCES] section from now on. <br />
			</comment>
		</revision>

		<revision>
			<date>20 January 2004</date>
			<version>v1.29</version>
			<comment>
				- Minor adjustment to the routine that decides if a ROM lives in a resource. <br />
				This fixes the handling of shootgal/sg-01-0. <br />
			</comment>
		</revision>

		<revision>
			<date>31 December 2003</date>
			<version>v1.28</version>
			<comment>
				- Added knowledge of the atpsx resource. <br />
			</comment>
		</revision>

		<revision>
			<date>29 December 2003</date>
			<version>v1.27</version>
			<comment>
				- Added knowledge of the two new resources added in MAME v0.78. <br />
			</comment>
		</revision>

		<revision>
			<date>14 September 2003</date>
			<version>v1.26</version>
			<comment>
				- Changed names of Neo-Geo BIOS ROMs in the Nebula driver reader. <br />
			</comment>
		</revision>

		<revision>
			<date>25 August 2003</date>
			<version>v1.25</version>
			<comment>
				- Added knowledge of the seven new resources added in MAME v0.72.<br />
			</comment>
		</revision>

		<revision>
			<date>19 May 2003</date>
			<version>v1.24</version>
			<comment>
				- Added support for '[RESOURCES]' in RomCenter2 data files.<br />
			</comment>
		</revision>

		<revision>
			<date>19 May 2003</date>
			<version>v1.23</version>
			<comment>
				- Added a fix for the 'nodump' syntax of MAME v0.68.<br />
			</comment>
		</revision>

		<revision>
			<date>7 April 2003</date>
			<version>v1.22</version>
			<comment>
				- Fixed CMPro log scanner to support the syntax 'bad dump'. <br />
				- Added knowledge of konamigx resource.<br />
			</comment>
		</revision>

		<revision>
			<date>18 January 2003</date>
			<version>v1.21</version>
			<comment>
				- Removed 'cloneof neogeo' from 'neocd' in Nebula driver. <br />
				- Added knowledge of skns and stvbios resources.<br />
			</comment>
		</revision>

		<revision>
			<date>20 May 2002</date>
			<version>v1.20</version>
			<comment>
				- New resource ROMs in MAME listinfo are automatically detected. <br />
				- ClrMamePro log and Nebula driver loaders now use the STORE_ROM <br />
				macro (this makes -g work correctly, amongst other things). <br />
				- Improved -m (fix merging) behaviour for resource ROMs. <br />
				- Nebula drivers now output the correct 'romof' for Neo-Geo clones.<br />
			</comment>
		</revision>

		<revision>
			<date>22 April 2002</date>
			<version>v1.19</version>
			<comment>
				- Added support for the PGM resource.<br />
			</comment>
		</revision>

		<revision>
			<date>20 April 2002</date>
			<version>v1.18</version>
			<comment>
				- Increased maximum number of samples to 10,000 (for PinMAME). <br />
				- Exceeding the sample limit now results in a graceful exit.<br />
			</comment>
		</revision>

		<revision>
			<date>4 April 2002</date>
			<version>v1.17</version>
			<comment>
				- Made 'fix-merging' option check the CRC as well as the name. <br />
				- Fix merging option warns of CRC conflicts it finds. Useful test! <br />
				- Strips trailing spaces from Nebula ROM names (for convenience). <br />
				- Executable is called 'datutil.exe' again.<br />
			</comment>
		</revision>

		<revision>
			<date>29 March 2002</date>
			<version>v1.16</version>
			<comment>
				- Added Nebula driver support (useful for data file validation). <br />
				- Supports the new '0x' syntax of CMPro logs. <br />
				- ZIP scanner now removes '.Zip' from filenames (case sensitive). <br />
				- Increased maximum line length to 16384 bytes (for MAME history). <br />
				- Increased maximum number of ROMs to 75000. <br />
				- Exceeding the game or ROM limits now results in a graceful exit. <br />
				- Compiled with zlib v1.1.4 <br />
			</comment>
		</revision>

		<revision>
			<date>10 February 2002</date>
			<version>v1.15</version>
			<comment>
				- Enhanced Calice support to cope with Neo-Geo sound ROMs. <br />
				- Modified source to compile easily with CygWin (and FreeBSD?). <br />
			</comment>
		</revision>

		<revision>
			<date>11 November 2001</date>
			<version>v1.14</version>
			<comment>
				- Added knowledge of ng-lo.rom. <br />
			</comment>
		</revision>

		<revision>
			<date>27 September 2001</date>
			<version>v1.13</version>
			<comment>
				- Supports CPSE driver file. <br />
				- Added 'ignore funny size' option (-z) for non-arcade dats. <br />
				- Added 'make lower case' option (-l). Affects names and CRCs. <br />
				- Puts "s around empty CMPro header items. <br />
				- Fixed directory/zip scanner for ROM names containing spaces. <br />
				- Fixed zip scanner to strip uppercase '.ZIP' from game names. <br />
				- Improved the 'funny size' warning relating to RomCenter 2 dats.<br />
			</comment>
		</revision>

		<revision>
			<date>28 August 2001</date>
			<version>v1.12</version>
			<comment>
				- Supports new ROM loading introduced in Calice v0.3.8 to v0.4.4.<br />
			</comment>
		</revision>

		<revision>
			<date>28 June 2001</date>
			<version>v1.11</version>
			<comment>
				- Added some warnings for bad quality RomCenter dats <br />
				(wrong version number in header and missing ROM sizes).
			</comment>
		</revision>

		<revision>
			<date>23 June 2001</date>
			<version>v1.10</version>
			<comment>
				- Fixed detection of RAINE32 dat format. <br />
				- Improved ZIP scanner (not case sensitive when searching for zips).<br />
			</comment>
		</revision>

		<revision>
			<date>8 June 2001</date>
			<version>v1.9</version>
			<comment>
				- Added directory scanning feature (reads ZIPs and subdirectories). <br />
				- Calice loader now uses the main driver code, not 'verifyroms'. <br />
				- RomCenter 2 loader fixes missing 'romof' details automatically.<br />
			</comment>
		</revision>

		<revision>
			<date>18 May 2001</date>
			<version>v1.8</version>
			<comment>
				- Fixed a minor bug in the '-m' feature (bug introduced in v1.7). <br />
				- Now compiled with MinGW (no long filename problems on NT now). <br />
			</comment>
		</revision>

		<revision>
			<date>26 April 2001</date>
			<version>v1.7</version>
			<comment>
				- Added handling of decocass resource in MAME dats. <br />
				- Added load/save support for CMPro element 'clrmamepro' and ROMCenter headers. <br />
				- Added preliminary support for Calice Driver files. <br />
				- Added load support for ClrMamePro log files (i.e. to convert into a dat format). <br />
				- Further improved the '-m' feature ('fix merging' option). <br />
				- RomCenter2 save routine strips redundant 'merge' information from non-clones. <br />
				- DJGPP compilation now uses -Wall option. <br />
				- Can now be compiled with Microsoft Visual C++.<br />
			</comment>
		</revision>

		<revision>
			<date>22 February 2001</date>
			<version>v1.6</version>
			<comment>
				- Added option to improve MAME's merging information ('-m').<br />
			</comment>
		</revision>

		<revision>
			<date>6 February 2001</date>
			<version>v1.5</version>
			<comment>
				- Some handling of the playch10 and cvs resources in MAME dats. <br />
				- RomCenter 2 is now the default save format when converting CMPro dats.<br />
			</comment>
		</revision>

		<revision>
			<date>18 December 2000</date>
			<version>v1.4</version>
			<comment>
				- Mimic HWC support. <br />
				- New format to list game titles ('-f titlelist'). <br />
				- Year/Manufacturer support for formats that can include them. <br />
				- Can specify values for ROMCenter/ROMCenter2 headers. <br />
				- Remove clones factility ('-r'). <br />
				- GWC loader now understands '.speech' tags (System16 Beta). <br />
				- Callus95 Patch renamed 'directory' to 'parent'. Now supported. <br />
				- Auto sorts when converting to RomCenter format or a Title List. <br />
				- Improved sorting (ensures each parent precedes it's clones). <br />
				- RAINE and MESS files are converted to CMPro format by default. <br />
				- Fixed a problem with the '-g' option and RAINE gameinfo files. <br />
				- Increased maximum ROM size to 9 characters (~1GB) for U64Emu. <br />
				- Increased number of lines scanned when identifying CMPro dats. <br />
				- Source: Added a makefile and included a SAVE_ONLY_FORMAT. <br />
				- Source: Changed parameter passing (uses a structure now). <br />
				- Preliminary: 'Verify Merging' facility (currently disabled). <br />
			</comment>
		</revision>

		<revision>
			<date>19 May 2000</date>
			<version>v1.3</version>
			<comment>
				- RomCenter 2 support. <br />
				- New method of sorting (useful for RomCenter). <br />
				- Two EXEs. This is because the long ROM name version eats memory <br />
				and is slow on machines without much physical memory. <br />
				- Improved handling of invalid parents. <br />
				- Warns of funny ROM sizes. <br />
				- Generates log of warnings during conversion.<br />
			</comment>
		</revision>

		<revision>
			<date>28 April 2000</date>
			<version>v1.2</version>
			<comment>
				- Increased game/rom name length to 80 characters. <br />
				That's about it! <br />
			</comment>
		</revision>

		<revision>
			<date>8 April 2000</date>
			<version>v1.1</version>
			<comment>
				- Added support for JFF.TXT, Sparcade RAT and JAS Romlist. <br />
				- Increased maximum number of games from 4096 to 5000. <br />
				- Increased game/rom name length to 50 characters. <br />
				- Improved listinfo parser so that it can handle odd formatting. <br />
				- Other minor modifications. <br />
			</comment>
		</revision>

		<revision>
			<date>1 April 2000</date>
			<version>v1.0</version>
			<comment>
				- Initial version.<br />
			</comment>
		</revision>
	</revisions>
</tool>
